<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research and policy publications on James Ransom</title>
    <link>/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research and policy publications on James Ransom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 2022 NCEE leadership survey: How the pandemic will shape university leaders and their institutions</title>
      <link>/publications/ncee-leadership-survey-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ncee-leadership-survey-2022/</guid>
      <description>This report captures the views of 41 senior leaders from 25 universities on the future of leadership, and the careful balancing act they face between dealing with challenges and exploiting opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the Pandemic Will Shape University Leaders and Their Institutions</title>
      <link>/publications/pandemic-shape-university-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/pandemic-shape-university-leaders/</guid>
      <description>An article for HEPI (the Higher Education Policy Institute) sharing the results of a survey of university leaders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universities and ‘Place Promotion’ in West Yorkshire</title>
      <link>/publications/place-promotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/place-promotion/</guid>
      <description>This paper provides an overview of key issues shaping the contribution of universities to the promotion of place, and to attracting inward investment and increased trade into Yorkshire and the Humber, and in particular West Yorkshire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovery can be achieved through empowering our regions – including England’s south east</title>
      <link>/publications/recovery-through-empowering-regions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/recovery-through-empowering-regions/</guid>
      <description>Article for Science &amp;amp; Engineering South on regional collaborations between universities, colleges, healthcare, communities and business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universities and the UK’s economic recovery: an analysis of future impact</title>
      <link>/publications/analysis-future-impact-uuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/analysis-future-impact-uuk/</guid>
      <description>This report looks ahead at the predicted impact of UK universities over the next five years. It formed the centrepiece of Universities UK&amp;rsquo;s GettingResults campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universities can drive economic recovery if everyone plays their part</title>
      <link>/publications/universities-can-drive-economic-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/universities-can-drive-economic-recovery/</guid>
      <description>In an article for Wonkhe, I set out what it will take for universities to play the fullest possible role in bouncing back post-pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rwanda Action Impact Report 2020</title>
      <link>/publications/rwanda-action-impact-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/rwanda-action-impact-2020/</guid>
      <description>I produced this impact report assessing work in the rural districts of Nyamasheke and Rusizi in Rwanda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Size Matters: Completing the Jigsaw for Rural and Regional Productivity</title>
      <link>/publications/size-matters-jigsaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/size-matters-jigsaw/</guid>
      <description>Article co-authored with Matthew Guest, published in the Journal of Applied Business and Economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Heads of Enterprise Report 2020: unlocking entrepreneurship in education</title>
      <link>/publications/ncee-enterprise-survey-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ncee-enterprise-survey-2020/</guid>
      <description>This report, Unlocking Entrepreneurship In Education, provides a snapshot of enterprise activity in UK higher education institutions at the time the COVID-19 pandemic struck. It reveals the data on how this activity has changed over the past eight years, and presents a summary of a landscape which is now undergoing unprecedented change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart cities research summary: Channel News Asia radio interview</title>
      <link>/publications/cna-radio-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/cna-radio-interview/</guid>
      <description>James Ransom interviewed by Daniel Martin on the Life&amp;amp;Style show on CNA938, a news and current affairs radio station in Singapore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rwanda Action Impact Report 2019</title>
      <link>/publications/rwanda-action-impact-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/rwanda-action-impact-2019/</guid>
      <description>An impact report assessing the work of Rwanda Action, a charity tackling deeply-entrenched poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research and innovation clusters policy briefing</title>
      <link>/publications/research-and-innovation-clusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/research-and-innovation-clusters/</guid>
      <description>Policy briefing on research and innovation clusters published by the Royal Society. I provided support for the analysis, and wrote the case studies for Israel, Pittsburgh, and Uppsala.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Levelling Up Yorkshire and Humber: health as the new wealth post-COVID</title>
      <link>/publications/levelling-up-yorkshire-humber/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/levelling-up-yorkshire-humber/</guid>
      <description>I was lead author for this report with the NHS Confederation, the Yorkshire &amp;amp; Humber Academic Health Science Network, and Yorkshire Universities on how different sectors can work together to improve health outcomes at a regional level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2019 NCEE leadership survey: Changes and challenges facing university leadership</title>
      <link>/publications/ncee-leadership-survey-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ncee-leadership-survey-2019/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of a survey of over 50 higher education leaders on what they think about leadership and the future of the sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New wave of smart cities has arrived – and they’re nothing like science fiction</title>
      <link>/publications/new-wave-of-smart-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/new-wave-of-smart-cities/</guid>
      <description>Smart cities are more likely to be defined by quieter upgrades to existing infrastructure and new partnerships that better represent residents. Article for &lt;em&gt;The Conversation&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart places – how universities are shaping a new wave of smart cities</title>
      <link>/publications/smart-places/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/smart-places/</guid>
      <description>This report, commissioned by the British Council, is about how universities can help solve the challenges faced by cities and towns. It is written for university leaders, city leaders and officials looking to form stronger partnerships with their universities. Examples are given of universities working with city hall in eight cities across Europe: Bucharest (Romania), Darmstadt (Germany), Dublin (Ireland), Lille (France), Milan (Italy), Nottingham (UK), Warsaw (Poland) and Zaragoza (Spain).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University Heads of Enterprise Report 2018: inspiring entrepreneurship in education</title>
      <link>/publications/ncee-enterprise-survey-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/ncee-enterprise-survey-2018/</guid>
      <description>This report reveals the state of enterprise and entrepreneurial education in the UK drawing on a survey by NCEE and ACS International Schools of 62 Heads of Enterprise from UK universities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write an engagement strategy</title>
      <link>/publications/how-to-write-engagement-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/how-to-write-engagement-strategy/</guid>
      <description>In this article for Wonkhe, I ask what university strategies and a psychology experiment from the 1940s have in common.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The city as a focus for university internationalisation: four European examples</title>
      <link>/publications/city-university-internationalisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/city-university-internationalisation/</guid>
      <description>Academic article in &lt;em&gt;Compare: A Journal of Comparative and International Education&lt;/em&gt; Volume 48, Issue 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universities: harnessing their superpowers</title>
      <link>/publications/universities-harnessing-superpowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/universities-harnessing-superpowers/</guid>
      <description>A report for KPMG UK on universities, societal challenges and city-building, based on research conducted in Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universities have the power to create exciting, connected and inclusive cities – here’s how</title>
      <link>/publications/universities-create-connected-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/universities-create-connected-cities/</guid>
      <description>Cities and universities can overcome social divides and create better places, but only if they work together. Article for &lt;em&gt;The Conversation&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutual influence? Universities, cities and the future of internationalisation</title>
      <link>/publications/mutual-influence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/mutual-influence/</guid>
      <description>A report commissioned by the British Council, exploring ways in which university and city leaders can plan international activity based on four case studies: Amsterdam, Dublin, Glasgow and Hannover.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connected Universities, Connected Cities</title>
      <link>/publications/connected-universities-connected-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/connected-universities-connected-cities/</guid>
      <description>A short thinkpiece commissioned by KPMG on a new era of university-city partnerships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Future of cities: universities and cities</title>
      <link>/publications/future-of-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/future-of-cities/</guid>
      <description>An essay for the UK Government Office for Science which looks at the links between cities and universities and explores how they can work together to solve societal problems and help future cities grow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replicating Data Mining Techniques for Development: A Case Study of Corruption</title>
      <link>/publications/data-mining-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/data-mining-for-development/</guid>
      <description>MSc thesis which looks at how small civil society organisations can adapt big data for international development applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Commonwealth Scholarships in the United Kingdom: Assessing impact in the health sector</title>
      <link>/publications/commonwealth-scholarships-health-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/commonwealth-scholarships-health-impact/</guid>
      <description>Whilst working at the Association of Commonwealth Universities I wrote an evaluation report of the impact of development scholarships in the health sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘A Little Marshall Plan’: Britain and the formation of the European Payments Union, 1948–50</title>
      <link>/publications/a-little-marshall-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/a-little-marshall-plan/</guid>
      <description>Academic article published in the &lt;em&gt;International History Review&lt;/em&gt;, examining the negotiations leading to the creation of the European Payments Union in 1950 as part of the Marshall Plan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
