<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Report on James Ransom</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/types/report/</link><description>Recent content in Report on James Ransom</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jcransom.com/types/report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building the Jigsaw</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/building-the-jigsaw/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/building-the-jigsaw/</guid><description>This report analyses the role of smaller and specialist universities in their local, national and international economies. I researched and wrote the five case studies, covering 11 UK higher education institutions.</description></item><item><title>The future impact of the members of Yorkshire Universities: an assessment</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/future-impact-yorkshire-universities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/future-impact-yorkshire-universities/</guid><description>This research uses historic data to predict the future impact of the twelve members of Yorkshire Universities: the universities of Bradford, Huddersfield, Hull, Leeds, Leeds Beckett, Leeds Trinity, Leeds Arts, Sheffield, Sheffield Hallam, York, and York St John, as well as the Leeds Conservatoire.</description></item><item><title>The 2022 NCEE leadership survey: How the pandemic will shape university leaders and their institutions</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/ncee-leadership-survey-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/ncee-leadership-survey-2022/</guid><description>This report captures the views of 41 senior leaders from 25 universities on the future of leadership, and the careful balancing act they face between dealing with challenges and exploiting opportunities.</description></item><item><title>Universities and ‘Place Promotion’ in West Yorkshire</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/place-promotion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/place-promotion/</guid><description>This paper provides an overview of key issues shaping the contribution of universities to the promotion of place, and to attracting inward investment and increased trade into Yorkshire and the Humber, and in particular West Yorkshire.</description></item><item><title>Universities and the UK’s economic recovery: an analysis of future impact</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/analysis-future-impact-uuk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/analysis-future-impact-uuk/</guid><description>This report looks ahead at the predicted impact of UK universities over the next five years. It formed the centrepiece of Universities UK&amp;rsquo;s GettingResults campaign.</description></item><item><title>Rwanda Action Impact Report 2020</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/rwanda-action-impact-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/rwanda-action-impact-2020/</guid><description>I produced this impact report assessing work in the rural districts of Nyamasheke and Rusizi in Rwanda.</description></item><item><title>University Heads of Enterprise Report 2020: unlocking entrepreneurship in education</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/ncee-enterprise-survey-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/ncee-enterprise-survey-2020/</guid><description>This report, Unlocking Entrepreneurship In Education, provides a snapshot of enterprise activity in UK higher education institutions at the time the COVID-19 pandemic struck. It reveals the data on how this activity has changed over the past eight years, and presents a summary of a landscape which is now undergoing unprecedented change.</description></item><item><title>Rwanda Action Impact Report 2019</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/rwanda-action-impact-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/rwanda-action-impact-2019/</guid><description>An impact report assessing the work of Rwanda Action, a charity tackling deeply-entrenched poverty.</description></item><item><title>Research and innovation clusters policy briefing</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/research-and-innovation-clusters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/research-and-innovation-clusters/</guid><description>Policy briefing on research and innovation clusters published by the Royal Society. I provided support for the analysis, and wrote the case studies for Israel, Pittsburgh, and Uppsala.</description></item><item><title>Levelling Up Yorkshire and Humber: health as the new wealth post-COVID</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/levelling-up-yorkshire-humber/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/levelling-up-yorkshire-humber/</guid><description>I was lead author for this report with the NHS Confederation, the Yorkshire &amp;amp; Humber Academic Health Science Network, and Yorkshire Universities on how different sectors can work together to improve health outcomes at a regional level.</description></item><item><title>The 2019 NCEE leadership survey: Changes and challenges facing university leadership</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/ncee-leadership-survey-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/ncee-leadership-survey-2019/</guid><description>Analysis of a survey of over 50 higher education leaders on what they think about leadership and the future of the sector.</description></item><item><title>Smart places – how universities are shaping a new wave of smart cities</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/smart-places/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/smart-places/</guid><description>This report, commissioned by the British Council, is about how universities can help solve the challenges faced by cities and towns. It is written for university leaders, city leaders and officials looking to form stronger partnerships with their universities. Examples are given of universities working with city hall in eight cities across Europe: Bucharest (Romania), Darmstadt (Germany), Dublin (Ireland), Lille (France), Milan (Italy), Nottingham (UK), Warsaw (Poland) and Zaragoza (Spain).</description></item><item><title>University Heads of Enterprise Report 2018: inspiring entrepreneurship in education</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/ncee-enterprise-survey-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/ncee-enterprise-survey-2018/</guid><description>This report reveals the state of enterprise and entrepreneurial education in the UK drawing on a survey by NCEE and ACS International Schools of 62 Heads of Enterprise from UK universities.</description></item><item><title>Universities: harnessing their superpowers</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/universities-harnessing-superpowers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/universities-harnessing-superpowers/</guid><description>A report for KPMG UK on universities, societal challenges and city-building, based on research conducted in Canada.</description></item><item><title>Mutual influence? Universities, cities and the future of internationalisation</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/mutual-influence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/mutual-influence/</guid><description>A report commissioned by the British Council, exploring ways in which university and city leaders can plan international activity based on four case studies: Amsterdam, Dublin, Glasgow and Hannover.</description></item><item><title>Connected Universities, Connected Cities</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/connected-universities-connected-cities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/connected-universities-connected-cities/</guid><description>A short thinkpiece commissioned by KPMG on a new era of university-city partnerships.</description></item><item><title>Evaluating Commonwealth Scholarships in the United Kingdom: Assessing impact in the health sector</title><link>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/commonwealth-scholarships-health-impact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.jcransom.com/publications/commonwealth-scholarships-health-impact/</guid><description>Whilst working at the Association of Commonwealth Universities I wrote an evaluation report of the impact of development scholarships in the health sector.</description></item></channel></rss>